💌 fdjeumou@utexas.edu | 🏶 franckdjeumou.github.io | 🖸 wuwushrek | 🛅 franck-djeumou-626613202 | 📓 Franck Djeumou

Research Interests_

My research lies broadly at the intersection of learning with prior knowledge, reinforcement learning, control theory, formal methods, and optimization. My research particularly aims to build autonomous systems that can learn how to operate in the real world while respecting underlying data, computational, safety, and perception limitations. Specifically, the recurrent theme in my work is that data alone is never the only source of knowledge available for learning. By deriving formal techniques to incorporate prior knowledge into learning, I have shown significant improvement in data efficiency, explainability, and generalization to unseen tasks or environments. Furthermore, I have demonstrated how to use such knowledge for the formal verification of the systems, particularly in the context of safety-critical applications such as aircraft control and robotics.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

September 2018 - August 2023

- Ph.D. Advisor: Ufuk Topcu
- Cumulative GPA Over 30 Credits (Ph.D. Major Course Requirements): 3.96

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE AND MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

ISAE-SUPAERO (Institut Supérieur de l'Aéronautique et de l'Espace)

Toulouse, France

September 2014 - June 2018

- · Advised by Prof. Jerome Hugues
- Cumulative GPA: 3.8 | Top 6% of the class
- Thesis on "Safety Guarantees for Drones through Set-Based Formal Verification Methods"

École Polytechnique

Palaiseau, France

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMASIC)

September 2016 - September 2017

- · Advised by Prof. Eric Goubault and Prof. Sylvie Putot
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7 | Graduated with Honours
- Thesis on "Human-Embedded Autonomous Flight Under Formal Task Specifications"
- · This master degree was obtained as a collaboration between ISAE-SUPAERO and École Polytechnique

Lycée Fénelon Paris, France

CLASS PREPARATORY (EQUIVALENT TO JUNIOR UNDERGRADUATE LEVEL) IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS, AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011 - June 2014

· Graduated with honours

Experience

Autonomous Systems Group

Austin, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

September 2018 - Present

- Published 10 conference papers (with one currently under review) and 6 journal papers (with 2 papers currently under review)
- · Collaborated with researchers from various international academic institutions, national research laboratories and companies, and presented research outcomes at more than 10 invited talks

Toyota Research Institute (TRI)

Los Altos, USA

RESEARCH INTERN

June 2022 - August 2022

- · Physics-informed neural networks models for model predictive control at the limits of stability of vehicle dynamics
- Autonomous drifting with 3 minutes of driving data

Cosynus Team at Laboratory LIX of École Polytechnique

Palaiseau, France

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISORS: ERIC GOUBAULT AND SYLVIE PUTOT

March 2018 - August 2018

- Designed and Built the quadrotor testbed for the research team based on Crazyflie drones
- · Implemented a hardware and software in the loop, Gazebo-based swarm simulator for the Crazyflie drones
- The code for the simulator is publicly available at www.ushrek/sim_cf and has over 20 stars and 20 forks on GitHub
- Investigated safety of dynamical systems through Taylor-based methods and abstract interpretation
- · Investigated on-the-fly, lightweight and real-time verification (reach and safety properties) algorithms to be embedded on Crazyflie drones

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

March 2017 - August 2017

- Designed and built quadrotors based on the Snapdragon Platform and PX4 as the autopilot. Implemented a fast trajectory generator for quadrotors based on the minimum snap approach via a new problem modeling
- · Investigated human interface with virtual reality and autonomous flight of a quadrotor via eye-tracking (youtube.com/watch?v=AfosHcWR9M)
- Investigated the problem of tracking moving targets using POMDPs (Partially Observable Markov Decision Process) and human inputs
- · Designed model checking and planning algorithms for UAVs autonomous missions with specifications expressed in temporal logic

Liebherr Aerospace and Transportation

Toulouse, France

2023

2022

2022

2021

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

June 2015 - August 2015

- Implementation in R of supervised learning algorithms to automatically classify aircraft's equipments from a reliability point of view
- · Designed and implemented an application in Java that interacts with Liebherr's database to provide classification results to an expert

Skills

Languages French (native), English (fluent), Japanese (beginner)

Python, C++, C, Java, R, Matlab, HTML5/CSS3 | My GitHub stats estimate more than 100k lines of code **Programming**

Tools & Technologies ROS, JAX, TensorFlow, Unity, Gazebo, PX4 Autopilot, Crazyflie, MuJoCo, RTOS, CVXPY, Gurobi, Mosek, Arduino

Publications

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE ARTICLES [10]

Autonomous Drifting with 3 Minutes of Data via Learned Tire Models

Franck Djeumou, Jonathan Goh, Ufuk Topcu, Avinash Balachandran

Submitted at IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation(ICRA)

URL: Processing

Taylor-Lagrange Neural Ordinary Differential Equations: Toward Fast Training and Evaluation of Neural ODEs

Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)

URL: https://www.ijcai.org/proceedings/2022/0405.pdf 2022

Neural Networks with Physics-Informed Architectures and Constraints for Dynamical Systems Modeling

Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC

URL: https://proceedings.mlr.press/v168/djeumou22a/djeumou22a.pdf 2022

Learning to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial: Data-Driven Control with Scarce Data and Side Information

Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC)

URL: https://proceedings.mlr.press/v168/djeumou22b/djeumou22b.pdf 2022

Task-Guided Inverse Reinforcement Learning Under Partial Information

Franck Djeumou, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS

URL: https://ojs.aaai.org/index.php/ICAPS/article/view/19785

Blending Controllers via Multi-Objective Bandits

Parham Gohari*, Franck Djeumou*, Abraham P Vinod, Ufuk Topcu American Control Conference (ACC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9867486

Learning-Based, Safety-Constrained Control from Scarce Data via Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)

URL: https://cverginis.github.io/publications/conferences/CDC21_safety.pdf

On-the-fly, Data-driven Reachability Analysis and Control of Unknown Systems: An F-16 Aircraft Case Study (Best Demo/Poster Award) Franck Djeumou, Aditya Zutshi, Ufuk Topcu

International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (HSCC)

URL: https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3447928.3457355 2021

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Smooth Systems from Limited Data

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P. Vinod, Éric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

American Control Conference (ACC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9483367

Probabilistic Swarm Guidance Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)

URL: http://www.roboticsproceedings.org/rss16/p058.pdf

JOURNAL ARTICLES [6]

^{*} indicates equal contribution

Task-Guided IRL on POMDPs at Scale with Information Asymmetry

Franck Djeumou, Christian Ellis, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

Conditionally Accepted at the special issue VSI:Risk-Aware Autonomy for consideration at the journal of Artificial

Intelliaence

URL: Processing 2022

Probabilistic Control of Heterogeneous Swarms Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications: A Decentralized and Scalable Approach **Franck Djeumou**, Zhe Xu, Murat Cubuktepe, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEEE TAC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9779942

Safety-Constrained Learning and Control using Scarce Data and Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, **Franck Djeumou**, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEEE TAC)

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06526

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Systems: From Side Information to Performance Guarantees through Reachability

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P Vinod, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEEE TAC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9930630

Policy Synthesis for Switched Linear Systems with Markov Decision Process Switching

Bo Wu, Murat Cubuktepe, Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEEE TAC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=9691772

Online Synthesis for Runtime Enforcement of Safety in Multi-Agent Systems

Dhananjay Raju, Sudarshanan Bharadwaj, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Control of Network Systems (IEEE TCNS)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9362272

Honors & Awards

2022	Rising Star, Selected to participate at the 2022 Rising Stars in Aerospace (RSIA) Symposium hosted by the	Boulder, USA
	University of Colorado Boulder and sponsored by CU-Boulder, MIT AeroAstro, Stanford, and Penn State.	
2022	Rising Star, Selected to participate at the Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS) Rising Stars Workshop 2022 hosted by	Virginia, USA
	the University of Virginia Link Lab	
2022	Scholarship , Category 'Award Winners, Invited Speakers and Sponsors' at the 32nd International Conference on	Virtual, Singapore
	Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS)	
2021	Winner , Best Demo/Poster Award at Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Hybrid Systems:	Nashville, USA
	Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)	
2017	Scholarship, Foundation of Ecole Polytechnique	Palaiseau, France
2017	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2016	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2015	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2014	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France

Professional Services

WORKSHOPS ORGANIZED

Workshop on Safe and Reliable Robot Autonomy under Uncertainty

Philadelphia, USA

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

May 2022

Co-organizer

REVIEWER

I was a reviewer at the following journals and conferences.

- IEEE Open Journal of Control Systems (OJ-CSYS) (2022)
- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (2022)
- American Control Conference (2020, 2021)
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (2021)
- IFAC symposium system identification (2021)

Selected Talks_____

	Neural Networks with Physics-Informed Architectures and Constraints for Dynamical Systems	
2022	Modeling,	Atlanta, USA
	SIAM Conference on Uncertainty Quantification (UQ22)	
2021	Incorporating Physics-Based Knowledge into Neural Network Dynamics Models,	Austin, USA
	Galois Inc: Final Briefing for the Assured Autonomy Project	
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin, USA
	Lockheed Martin	Austin, OSA
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin, USA
	Texas Robotics Symposium	
2021	Data-Driven, On-The-Fly Reachability and Control of Unknown Systems,	
	Mini-Symposium on "Leaning for Dynamical Systems and Control" at the SIAM Conference on Applications of	Portland, USA
	Dynamical Systems	
2020	Learning On-the-Fly with a Case Study in Hypersonic Flight,	Austin, USA
	Sandia National Laboratories: Autonomy for Hypersonics Virtual Field Day	